So that's the...
Mutagen that turned us all
into what we are now.
Let's drink some!
What? Why would you do that?
'Cause if you mutate a mutant,
you get a super mutant!
Or a pile of goo
on the sidewalk.
Either way, it's an improvement.
Guys, this is huge.
Whoever kidnapped those
people are somehow connected
to what happened to
us 15 years ago.
How is that possible?
For alien robots,
anything is possible.
Stop that.
There are no such thing
as alien robots!
Oh, yeah?
Well, if there's no such thing
as alien robots, how
do you explain this?
Aah! Aah! My face!
Man, this mask is
glued on tight!
Mikey, stop! It's not a mask.
Okay. He's in the clear.
But those other guys were
totally alien robots.
Enough! Time to
get some answers.
Who are you, and
what's goin' on?
Name's snake, and I
got nothing to say
to you hideous freaks.
Oh, well, that's 'cause
you don't know us yet.
Ah!
See, we were just regular guys
until we got hit with
a little of this.
Whawhat are you doing?
Playing a little
game I like to call.
Mutation Roulette.
Now you could turn out
handsome like me,
or you might end up
disgusting and deformed,
like Mikey here.
Hey!
So, you feel lucky?
Okay, okay!
They call themselves the kraang.
They been grabbing scientists
from all over the city.
I'm right here.
What do they want
with scientists?
I don't know.
All I know is
they're taking them
out of the city tonight,
but I don't know where!
This is awesome! That
girl's dad is a scientist.
I'm a scientist.
She is so gonna like me.
I don't think you're her type.
Where are they now?
There's gotta be, like,
20 of them down there.
Yeah, and that's just
the ones we can see.
All right! An
all-you-can-beat buffet!
We can't just rush in there.
We need a plan.
- Why?
- Think, you shellbrain.
There are innocent
lives at stake.
If we screw this up,
they're all goners.
Then we won't screw it up.
Boy, I could sure go for some
of that pizza right now, huh?
What?
I can't be the only
one that's hungry.
Where's snake?
Oh, geez.
Get him!
- Maybe he went over the wall.
- I'm on it!
Alley-oop!
Uhh! Ah! Ugh! Aah!
Ow. I don't think
he went this way.
Oh, great. We let him get away.
Whoa, whoa. You're the leader.
That means you let him get away.
- You're not helping.
- I'm not trying to help.
Okay, okay. You want me to lead?
Fine.
We go back to the lair, gear up,
and at midnight, we
drive snake's van
right up to the gate.
They'll think we're him,
and we'll cruise right in.
And then we bust some heads?
And then we bust some heads.
I love a happy ending.
I know you're a little
worried about me.
Look, I'm not gonna lie to you.
We've never gone into
a fight like this,
and I don't know
what's gonna happen.
But you don't have to worry.
I will make it back.
I love you, man.
Aww.
Are you talking to
your pet turtle?
No. Shut up!
That's adorable.
Oh, I'm gonna crush you!
Aah!
I'm gonna shellac you!
I think this plan is gonna work.
No plan ever survives
contact with the enemy.
It is how you react
to the unexpected
that will determine if you
and your brothers succeed.
Sensei, do you think
I'm ready for this?
Leonardo, I made you
leader for a reason.
What is that reason?
That is for you to
discover on your own.
There's so much riding on this.
What if something goes wrong?
Failure is a possibility
every leader must
face, Leonardo.
It is something I had
to face in Japan
during my final battle with
my enemy, the shredder.
Years ago, oroku saki, as
shredder was called then,
had been my friend, but
the love of a woman
came between us.
He could not accept it, and
his jealousy turned outward
in a vengeful attack.
And while he could not
defeat me that day,
my world fell and
crumbled around me
as the battle took the life
of my beloved tang shen,
and I lost my baby
daughter, miwa.
But that's my point, sensei.
You lost everything.
I lost many things.
My family, my home, my name.
But I gained many things as
well, like the four of you.
Don't worry. We can handle this.
Get back here!
Hey, you can't keep
us in here like this!
We know our rights!
I don't think they care
about that, April.
We can't just sit here.
We've gotta do something.
Like what?
Oh, my stomach!
The pain is unbearable!
Ah!
Well, I guess we
can just sit here.
They'll be here any minute.
Kraang, are those who are coming
to this place coming
to this place?
I lack that knowledge, Kraang.
I will inquire of Kraang
about that knowledge.
Do you have the knowledge
if those coming to this place
are near this place, Kraang?
They're turtles!
Call them turtles! "Are
the turtles here?"
There are lights of a
vehicle which contain that
which you wish us
to call the turtles
coming to this place which
you wish us to call here.
What are you talking about?
Ah! Ah!
The ones coming to this place
are not in the vehicle
bringing them to this place.
Then in what place are the
ones called the turtles?
Wow, lucky thing that van
showed up to distract them.
Ow!
That was the plan, Mikey.
We knew snake was
hiding in the alley,
so Raph and I made him think
we would be in the van.
But we weren't in the van.
Just keep climbing.
Can do.
Wow, I've never seen
anything like this.
They're using a metal alloy
that I don't even recognize.
Gosh! A metal alloy even
you don't know about!
It boggles the mind.
Dude, you wanna talk
metallurgy with me?
- Bring it.
- I don't, and...
Guys! What part of
being in an enemy lair
do you not understand?
Whoa. Alien robots.
Alien robots, huh?
Hmm, where have I
heard that before?
Oh, yeah!
I've been saying it for hours!
Whoo!
Hwaah!
See? See? It's a brain thing!
I told you! I told you!
But did any of you believe me?
No!
'Cause you all think I'm
just some kind of bonehead!
Ow!
Uh! Ugh! Ah! Ah!
Mikey!
Okay!
But I was still right
about the brain thing.
You gotta give me that.
Let's move.
Move where?
I think those are
power conduits.
Oh! That's really interesting!
Thanks for sharing, Donnie.
Meathead, the conduits are
all converging that way,
which means that whatever is
going on in that direction
is important!
You got spanked.
Ow! Ow! Mercy!
Not cool.
We found 'em!
We'll hold them off!
You pick the lock.
Don't worry! I'll have you
out of there in a second.
Okay, giant lizard-thing.
A turtle, actually. I'm...
I'm Donatello.
- April.
- Wow, that's a pretty...
The lock, Donnie!
Yeahoh, right, yeah! Sorry.
Aaaaah!
Not to rush you, but hurry up!
Hey! You think it's easy
trying to pick a lock
with these hands?
Uh, sorry.
Oh, for the love of...
get out of my way!
Ah!
What?
No!
Huh?
Get the door!
That'll hold 'em.
What?
You are seriously twisted.
- Thanks.
- No! Let me go!
Let's get 'em!
Uh-oh.
You did this to me!
Now you're going to pay!
It's Snake!
He mutated into a... Giant weed!
That's weird.
You'd think he'd get
mutated into a snake.
Yeah, you would, if
you were an idiot.
But his name is Snake.
- So?
- You don't understand science.
I'll crush you turtles!
Uh, would it help if we
said it was an accident?
So, heh, I'll put
you down for a no?
Whoa!
Eww! Eww! Don't let it touch me!
Don't let it touch me!
Aah! It touched me!
Ahh.
It grew back?
No fair!
Donnie! Go!
Ah!
Oh!
And... Yuck.
Whoa! Aah!
Snakeweed is really powerful!
- Snakeweed?
- Yeah!
His name was Snake, and
now he's a weed, so...
We get it!
We just have to hold it off
until Donnie gets back.
While not getting
shot by alien robots.
- With brains!
- Let it go, man.
Huh?
What's the plan again, chief?
I'm working on it.
Whoa!
The power conduits.
Are we really gonna start
talking about that again?
Perfect. Raph! Mikey!
Oh, good!
For a second there, I thought
this was gonna be too easy!
Whoa! Whoa! Aah!
Hold on! I'm coming!
Aah!
You okay?
Dad.
- Aah!
- Whoa!
What are they doing?
They're leading him straight
toward that power generator!
That's incredibly stupid!
Or brilliant. Or... or both!
Aah! Ow!
Hey, come and get me, stinkweed!
Kraang, the ones in this
place are not in this place
where they were.
The ones are called
turtles, Kraang.
They are dangerous
to what we are doing
in this place and other places.
Yes, I am knowledge of that.
The turtles must be
eliminated from all places.
Are you gonna be all right?
I guess.
My aunt says I can stay here
as long as I want,
but I'll be a lot better
when I track down the
creeps that took my dad.
- Won't the police help?
- Funny thing.
When you tell them your dad
was kidnapped by alien brains
in robot bodies, they don't
take you all that seriously.
I hear that.
April, I promise you
we will not rest
until we find him.
- We won't?
- No, we won't.
Thank you, but it's
not your fight.
Yes, it is.
I am impressed, Leonardo.
You proved to be an
effective leader
under the most difficult
of circumstances.
Thank you, sensei.
And I think I figured out
why you made me leader.
Oh? Why is that?
Because you sensed inside
me a true warrior's spirit
that could forge us
all into the heroes
we are destined to become.
- No.
- No?
Then why did you make me leader?
Because you asked.
That's it?
But you seemed so
certain you were right.
As a leader, you will learn
that there is no
right and wrong,
only choices.
So you could have
chosen any of us?
- Yes.
- Even Mikey?
No.
- That would have been wrong.
- Everybody!
Come here! We made the news!
A report of... get this...
ninjas in New York.
Don't believe me?
After residents
reported a disturbance,
the police recovered this.
For channel six news, this is.
- Carlos Chang O'Brien...
- Gambe
saying, "Hi-ya!"
This is awesome!
We're gonna be famous!
You must be more careful.
The ninja's most powerful
weapon is the shadows.
Being brought out into the
light is a dangerous thing.
Relax, sensei. It's one
little news story.
What's the worst
that can happen?
Ninjas in New York.
Don't believe me?
After residents
reported a disturbance,
the police recovered this.
Recovered this.
So my old enemy is in New York,
and training his own army.
At last, I can finish what
I started so long ago.
Prepare my jet.
I'm going to visit
an old friend.