- Yah!
- Oh, yeah!
Michelangelo is on the move!
Heeyah!
You don't know what to do.
I'm here, I'm there.
I could be anywhere.
How do you stop what
you can't even see?
Like that?
Good one, Leo.
All right, Donnie.
Put down the staff and
no one gets hurt.
Uh, you said that last time,
Raph, and then you hurt me.
Yeah, but less
than I would have.
Yeah, right.
Wah!
Ah!
Yah!
Should've dropped the staff?
Should've dropped the staff.
Okay, okay. Ow! I'm down!
Onegai shimasu.
Whatever you say.
Ah!
Agh!
Nice try.
Ya me!
You all did very well.
But I did better.
This is about
self-improvement, Raphael.
It is not about
winning and losing.
I know, sensei.
But I won and they lost.
Ah, ah, ah!
But what's really important
is that we all did our best.
Good job, everyone!
Ah.
♪ Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles ♪
♪ Heroes in a half
shell, turtle power ♪
♪ Here we go, it's a lean,
green, ninja team ♪
♪ Get rocked with the shell
shocked pizza kings ♪
♪ Can't stop these
radical dudes ♪
♪ The secret of the ooze
made the chosen few ♪
♪ Emerge from the shadows
to make their move ♪
♪ The good guys win and
the bad guys lose ♪
♪ Leonardo's the
leader in blue ♪
♪ Does anything it takes to
get his ninjas through ♪
♪ Donatello is a fellow,
has a way with machines ♪
♪ Raphael's got the most
attitude on the team ♪
♪ Michelangelo, he's
one of a kind ♪
♪ And you know just where to
find him when it's party time ♪
♪ Master splinter taught 'em
every single skill they need ♪
♪ To be one lean, mean,
green incredible team ♪
♪ Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles ♪
♪ Heroes in a half
shell, turtle power ♪
Mm.
Bleh!
There's a little more
algae and worms left
if anyone wants it.
Anybody? Anybody?
- No, thanks.
- I'm good.
All yours.
Well, I guess no one
left room for... Cake!
- Whoa!
- It is a cake!
Made of... algae...
and... worms.
What's the frosting made out of?
You don't wanna know.
Happy Mutation day!
Ah, yes.
15 years ago today, our
lives changed forever
and we became the
unlikeliest of families.
Tell us the story,
Master Splinter.
Michelangelo, I have already
told it many times.
Please! Pleeeease!
Please. It's the only
way to shut Mikey up.
Ah, very well.
Many years ago, when
I was still human,
I was leaving the pet store
with four baby turtles.
- That was us?
- Yes.
Don't interrupt!
I passed a strange
man on the street.
Something felt off about him.
I decided to follow.
Go no further.
This place is a place
where you are not allowed
to be in this place.
We have been seen in
this place by you,
so this is not a place
that will be left by you.
That was the beginning
of our life together.
It was the mysterious
substance in this canister
that, in a way, gave
birth to us all.
Mom.
So, sensei, now that we're 15,
I think we're finally ready to
go up to the surface, don't you?
Yes.
And no.
- Oh, man, come on.
- Lame.
I hate when he does that.
You have grown powerful,
but you are still young.
You lack the maturity to
use your skills wisely.
So, sensei, isn't that just no?
Yes...
And no.
Wisdom comes from experience.
And experience comes
from making mistakes.
Aha!
So in order for us
to gain the wisdom,
we have to make the mistakes.
- So we can go.
- No.
- And yes?
- No!
Oh!
Sensei, we know you're
trying to protect us,
but we can't spend our whole
lives hiding down here.
Mm.
You may go tonight.
High three!
Mr. Crenshaw, status report!
Status? I'll give
you the status!
We're gonna blow
up in two seconds!
Thank you, captain.
Gentlemen, I have a
bold and daring plan.
There's no time for hesitation.
My orders must be carried
out without question!
Aye, sir!
You know this show
is stupid, right?
Space Heroesis a great show.
And captain Ryan
is a great hero.
Someday, I am gonna
be just like him.
Well, you do like to
hear yourself talk,
so you're on your way.
It's go time!
You are going up to a
strange and hostile world.
You must maintain
awareness at all times.
Aye, sensei!
- Stay in the shadows.
- Aye, sensei!
- Don't talk to strangers.
- Everyone is a stranger.
- Aye, sensei!
Make sure you go
before you leave.
The restrooms up
there are filthy.
Sensei!
Good luck, my sons.
- I am so pumped!
- Surface time!
Oh, this is gonna be epic!
Look both ways before
crossing the street!
It's so beautiful.
The city is just
full of possibility.
There could be an adventure
around this corner...
Or... or this one...
Or this one!
There's not, but there could be!
Look at all the computers!
Is that the next generation
cadmium processor
with quantum encryption?
I don't know, Donatello. Is it?
- It is!
- Guys, guys!
Check this out.
A hand made out of light.
Now it's an eye
made out of light.
And the hand again!
Now the eye's back!
Now the hand!
- Come on, genius.
- The eye!
So where to next?
Huh?
Ah!
That was kinda fun.
We're too exposed out here.
Come on.
Pizza.
Should we open it?
Careful! It could be dangerous.
I think it's food.
It's not like any
food I ever saw.
I'll try it.
Mm! Mm.
Uh, yuck.
You guys won't like it.
I'll take the rest.
- No way!
- Nuh-uh!
Back off!
I never thought I'd
taste anything better
than worms and algae,
but this is amazing!
Right?
I love it up here!
Yeah-ha!
Whoohoo!
Ha, ha-ha!
Yippy! Ha ha!
All right, guys,
it's getting late.
We should probably
head back home.
Lame.
Guys! Look at that!
She's the most beautiful
girl I've ever seen.
Isn't she the only
girl you've ever seen?
My point still stands.
What?
What is this?
We gotta save 'em!
Splinter's instructions
were very clear.
We're supposed to stay
away from people.
And bathrooms.
I thought you wanted
to be a hero.
Since when do heroes
ask for permission?
They don't. But...
Well, I'm going!
Help!
Hey!
Still standing, huh?
I'll fix that.
- Wah!
- Oh!
- Watch it!
- You watch it!
Watch it, Donnie!
Hyah!
What the... Ah!
Oh, come on!
Ooh!
Oh! Ow!
Ha.
Hey, cut it out! Stop! Ow!
Huh? Agh!
Gotcha!
Aghh!
No, no, no. No. Don't worry.
We're the good guys.
It's okay.
Whoops! Sorry.
Watch out!
Huh?
They're getting away!
They got the girl!
You just jabbed me
with your sword.
Well, I didn't know you were
gonna land where I was stabbing.
You think you're tough, huh?
You think you're tough
enough to stand up
to my hot nunchuck fury?
Hyah! Wah!
Huh?
I see. Well, then...
Aah!
Stay back!
What the...
That is all kinds of wrong.
Aah!
Guys! Guys! You're never
gonna believe this!
That dude, he... he...
Had a brain!
We all have brains, Mikey.
Not all of us.
In our chests?
No, Mikey. Not in our chests.
You're not listening to me!
Did you just slap me?
I was calming you down.
Why would that calm me down?
I think he's delusional.
Just-just... come here.
I'm telling you.
The big guy was a robot
and he had a freaky-weird alien
brain thing in his chest.
You gotta believe me.
- I'm not sure we do.
- Oh, yeah?
Well, you'll change your tune
when you see that he's...
Gone?
And so your inability
to work together
allowed them all to get away.
Well, maybe if I didn't
have to waste time
arguing with hero boy,
I could've saved them.
Hey, if you hadn't
gotten in my way,
I could have done it.
And you went flying
off on your own.
How smart was that?
Well, it would've
worked out great
if somebody hadn't
hit me in the head
with their nunchucks!
Well, none of this
would've happened if...
Somebody hadn't trusted us to
go up there in the first place.
Oh, geez.
Sensei, I didn't mean to...
- No, Michelangelo.
- You are right.
- I am?
- He is?
You were not fully prepared
for what was up there.
I trained you to fight
as individuals,
not as a team.
And as your teacher,
your father,
the responsibility
for that is mine.
Perhaps in another
year we can try again.
Another year?
Ha! Has everybody forgotten
that people were kidnapped?
They don't have a year!
Sensei, we have to
do something now!
You weren't there, sensei.
You didn't see the way that
girl looked into my eyes.
She was scared.
And she was counting on me...
us... to save her!
Yes, you must save her.
I agree, sensei.
But in that fight,
we weren't exactly a
well-oiled machine.
Like that robot with
the brain thingy.
Give a rest!
Hmm.
If you are to fight more
effectively as a unit,
you are going to need a leader.
Can I be the leader?
Why should you be the leader?
I kicked your butt. I
should be the leader.
Hey, I'm smarter than all
you guys put together.
- It should be me.
- No way!
It should be me!
I don't really have a reason. I
just think it would be neat.
This is a difficult decision.
I will meditate on it.
It's Leonardo.
No hard feelings, Raph?
Stick it in your shell.
Explain to me one more time
what we're doing here.
Mikey, we've been over this.
That building has the same
logo as the van that was used
to kidnap the family.
So if we wait here long enough,
one of the kidnappers will
eventually show his face.
And when he does, we'll
make him tell us
where they took them.
And then we got ourselves a van!
Just hit the guy I tell you to.
Will do!
Are you sure this is gonna work?
Trust me. They'll
be here any second.
Oh!
Okay, I'm thinking
of something green.
Ga-reen. Ga-reen.
Is it Raphael again?
Man, you're good at this!
Give it up already. The
guy's not gonna show.
We have to be patient.
No, you have to come
up with a better plan,
'cause the four of
us standing here
with our thumbs up our noses...
I don't think they'd fit.
Is pointless.
You sure about that, Raph?
He just showed up, didn't he?
I should've complained
two hours ago.
Gentlemen, I have a
bold and daring plan.
There's no time for hesitation.
My orders must be carried
out without question.
Guys? Guys, wait up!
All right, buddy.
We can do this the easy way,
or... my vote... the hard way.
Yeah, look at it logically.
There are four of
us and one of you.
What are you gonna do?
- Yow!
- Whoa!
You had to ask!
- He's getting away again!
- No, he's not.
Whoa!
Ugh.
Now we're getting somewhere.
I don't know what that means.
Go around back.
Why didn't he just say so?
Huh?
Mom?